MC Xiaoyang: Hello everyone, welcome to
MC Xiaoyang: Let's Start Deduction Season 4 PD Whispers.
MC Xiaoyang: The people sitting here today
MC Xiaoyang: are the designers of our door-pushing game,
MC Xiaoyang: the PDs behind our players.
MC Xiaoyang: If what the audience sees are
MC Xiaoyang: the players inside the game instances,
MC Xiaoyang: then what the PDs see
MC Xiaoyang: is the most real side of them outside their roles.
MC Xiaoyang: Now let's have our PDs say hello.
MC Xiaoyang: Welcome.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Hello everyone, I'm Bro Ning's PD, Xiaoqi.
Jin Jing PD Lulu: Hello everyone, I'm Jin Jing's PD, Wang Lu.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Hello everyone.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I'm Bro Zhang's PD, Weiwei.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: I'm Xiaoding's PD, Dada.
Zhou Keyu PD Shiyi: Hello everyone, I'm Keyu's PD, Shiyi.
MC Xiaoyang: Welcome. Welcome, everyone.
MC Xiaoyang: You're all old friends of ours.
MC Xiaoyang: On camera,
what we see is the players solving cases and keeping each other company.
MC Xiaoyang: what we see is the players
MC Xiaoyang: solving cases and keeping each other company.
MC Xiaoyang: But off camera,
MC Xiaoyang: the PDs also remember many
MC Xiaoyang: unbroadcast moments
MC Xiaoyang: of their earnest, cute, and warm interactions.
MC Xiaoyang: Next, we will
MC Xiaoyang: take our time to chat with each of you.
Yeah.
MC Xiaoyang: Let's start with Bro Ning.
As for Bro Ning...
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Just like in the previous seasons,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: I've said this before,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Bro Ning is a
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: very earnest
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and dedicated person.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Whenever he does something,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: he tries his best to do it perfectly.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: And this point
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: is something that, throughout these seasons,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: I've felt has remained consistent
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: from beginning to end.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He always wants to give us the best results,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and he puts his utmost effort
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and sincerity into Let's Start Deduction.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: When we record the show,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: we usually,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: the day before the recording,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: go to our guests to go over their Character Cards,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: the Character Cards they receive,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and their own personal backstories.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: And every time, Bro Ning...
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: his habit hasn't changed either.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Every time, he says he'll look at it first,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: read through it,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: digest it,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and then discuss it with me.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: We talk about our understanding of the character's story.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Then he would add to his character,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: fleshing it out with designs he thought of.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: For example, during the seventh case, they wore
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: a security guard uniform.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: During the fitting,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: the bags they were carrying
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: were empty.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: There were no props in them.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Then Bro Ning thought,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: when a security guard is on normal patrol,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: he would want to add some details.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Like, "I want to put a walkie-talkie
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: or a baton inside."
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He hoped that the next day, on everyone's uniforms,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: whoever had an empty bag
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: would carry some of these little gears.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: It's helping to fill in these details
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: that gives the character authenticity.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Bro Ning would think about it himself
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and fill in the gaps.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: And then, every time
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: after we go over the character card,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: this is also something that
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: hasn't changed over the past seasons.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Every time we go over the card,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Bro Ning always tells me
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: to leave a copy with him.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: The next day during hair and makeup,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: he keeps reading and memorizing it.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He commits it to memory.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He'd think about it the next day:
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: how he could tell
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: his story more completely
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and with a better rhythm.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He memorizes more card details.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He never acts like,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: "I've recorded this for so many years
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and I'm so familiar with this format,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: so I can put in less effort."
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He's always thinking about how to
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: do a better job with the task at hand.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He always takes it very seriously.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: And another thing is,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: during the fifth and sixth cases,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: we had a historical costume theme.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: We had a lot of outdoor movement,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: like walking on the streets
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: or taking a boat.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Moving around outdoors is definitely
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: much more tiring than indoors.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: And it was really hot at that time.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: To ensure a good outcome, Bro Ning
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: still wore his headpiece for two days.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He even rallied everyone, saying,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: "Let's all get a bit more immersed."
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: When we recorded the fifth case,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: at the start of the first costume day,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Bro Ning told everyone,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: "Let's get a bit more immersed,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and bring out that historical vibe."
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: He said, "It's rare for us to
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: do a proper historical theme.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: And the production team
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: worked hard to build this set.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: Since we have this costume script,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: let's try to play it well
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and bring out that feeling."
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: So, from all these details,
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: you can feel how dedicated he is
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: and how much he wants to do this well.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: And another thing is he analyzes
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: his own state when playing the killer.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He would talk about
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: how he used to play it in the past
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: when he was the killer,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: and how he wants...
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: If he gets the killer role again this year,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: he wants to change his approach.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He wants to break away from his past
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: way of playing the killer.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He wants to change his strategy
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: to bring everyone some surprises.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: Following his train of thought,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: you'll feel that Brother Ning
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: is a very...
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He's someone who really puts thought into it.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He will put a lot of effort into
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: handling every single detail.
MC Xiaoyang: Actually, we often see Brother Ning...
MC Xiaoyang: When he comes over to shoot promos,
MC Xiaoyang: we can feel that he's always thinking.
MC Xiaoyang: He's always in a state of deep thought.
MC Xiaoyang: And he'll also be...
MC Xiaoyang: muttering to himself while resting,
MC Xiaoyang: or just sitting there,
MC Xiaoyang: constantly thinking about the cases.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: There are many moments this year
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: that make me feel like Brother Ning
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: is truly amazing.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: For example, he's great at decoding clues.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: I think everyone has noticed this too.
MC Xiaoyang: Indeed.
MC Xiaoyang: Deciphering...
MC Xiaoyang: It consists of decoding...
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: And reading.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: Let me talk about decoding first, which is analyzing.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: After finding a clue during an evidence search,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: every time he finds one,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: he can digest it very quickly.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: And he can accurately analyze
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: what new information this clue
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: brings us at this current stage,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: what this new information means,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: and therefore,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: what direction it leads us in,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: and what we need to solve next.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: For this whole deductive reasoning process,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: he can grasp it very quickly.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: Without a god's-eye view,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: I think being able to do it
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: to his extent is very difficult.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: But Brother Ning can always,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: amidst scattered information,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: grasp that precise key point,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: that correct answer.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He can pull out the main storyline.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: So sometimes when I listen to him
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: analyze these clues
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: so quickly,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: in just a few words,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: concisely completing
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: the deduction process,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: I just get this feeling of...
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: And the other point is reading.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: As for reading, I think everyone noticed too,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: Brother Ning's reading of clues
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: has become his personal skill.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: His voice sounds really nice, too.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: It's not like he
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: has the chance to
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: get the clues in advance,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: familiarize himself with them a few times,
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: and then read them.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He finds them on the spot
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: and reads them immediately.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: He relies on his vocal skills... LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: combined with his line delivery... LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: to make these written words come alive. LET'S START DEDUCTION
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: He played a very spot-on Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: and even extraordinary role. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: For example, one instance is Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: Ningbo Weibu's letter from ep 5, Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: his suicide note. Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: Since it was set in the past, Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: that letter was formatted, well, Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: written vertically, right to left. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: And on top of that, Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: the phrasing was a bit archaic. Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: Plus, it was in handwritten font. Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: During our several playtests, Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: no one read that letter well. Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: Everyone stumbled while reading. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Dada: Because it's indeed quite different Start Deduction
PD Dada: from our usual reading habits. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Dada: But it was Bro Ning's first time, Start Deduction
PD Dada: yet he read it perfectly every time. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: Right. Start Deduction
MC Xiaoyang: Because Bro Ning's performance Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
MC Xiaoyang: with that letter went viral. Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: I was actually a bit surprised. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: Since no one read it well before, Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: we were worried that Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: the effect of reading it on site Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: wouldn't be that good, Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: making it less immersive for all. Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: But the effect Bro Ning Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: presented is what everyone saw. Start Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: He really read it very fluently. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: Moreover, his voice Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: and the vibe fit perfectly. Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
PD Xiaoqi: His phrasing was also great. Deduction
PD Xiaoqi: Listening to it at the time was... Deduction
PD Xiao Qi: He read it so smoothly.
PD Xiao Qi: I really wanted to applaud Brother Ning.
Yeah.
MC Xiao Yang: The first time I saw that clip,
MC Xiao Yang: when he was reading it, I felt a bit...
MC Xiao Yang: It was really touching.
MC Xiao Yang: It made me want to cry a little.
MC Xiao Yang: Just watching him...
MC Xiao Yang: when he read that segment.
PD Xiao Qi: Yes.
PD Xiao Qi: And another thing
PD Xiao Qi: is his improvisation skills.
PD Xiao Qi: You really have to admit that his improv skills
PD Xiao Qi: are a truly impressive point.
PD Xiao Qi: Like in the fifth case,
PD Xiao Qi: with the Ningbo Weibu Character Card.
PD Xiao Qi: Because it was his first time getting an Amnesia Script,
PD Xiao Qi: and this one also...
PD Xiao Qi: It was a script with very little information.
PD Xiao Qi: So he only had
PD Xiao Qi: a tiny bit,
PD Xiao Qi: a tiny description of when he opened his eyes.
PD Xiao Qi: I mean, for things like
PD Xiao Qi: what the Deduction Madness Three Kingdoms was,
PD Xiao Qi: he didn't even know this common knowledge.
PD Xiao Qi: He had to rely entirely on the live recording.
PD Xiao Qi: During the live recording, he had to listen
PD Xiao Qi: to the information others shared,
PD Xiao Qi: and absorb it right there on the spot.
PD Xiao Qi: And in the stories of others,
PD Xiao Qi: they all had some sort of grudge with him.
PD Xiao Qi: So while listening, he also had to
PD Xiao Qi: figure out their character relationships.
PD Xiao Qi: Then he had to interact with other guests,
PD Xiao Qi: and he also had to deduce and analyze the case.
PD Xiao Qi: All of this was truly improvised.
PD Xiao Qi: He managed to pull it all off perfectly.
PD Xiao Qi: In that moment, you couldn't help but admire him,
PD Xiao Qi: and you'd also feel really moved.
PD Xiao Qi: This feeling of being moved comes from...
PD Xiao Qi: you know, when the setups we designed
PD Xiao Qi: are beautifully,
PD Xiao Qi: and even exceptionally executed by him.
PD Xiao Qi: When they are presented
PD Xiao Qi: with such great results,
PD Xiao Qi: you get this feeling as a creator...
MC Xiao Yang: Exactly.
Yeah.
PD Xiao Qi: And there are also some really amazing things.
PD Xiao Qi: Then you'll find him kind of cute.
PD Xiao Qi: Like when he played Pitch-Pot and got it in one try.
PD Xiao Qi: Because we tested it many times back then,
Yeah.
PD Xiao Qi: it's very hard to hit.
PD Xiao Qi: The normal result of our tests was
PD Xiao Qi: throwing all the arrows and missing every single one.
MC Xiao Yang: Right.
PD Xiao Qi: And he got it in one go.
PD Xiao Qi: Then you could see him slightly...
PD Xiao Qi: feeling like he was pretty awesome himself.
PD Xiao Qi: But he wouldn't make it too obvious.
PD Xiao Qi: It just makes you feel he's...
MC Xiao Yang: That Pitch-Pot bullseye in one try,
MC Xiao Yang: it was really quite shocking.
MC Xiao Yang: Because when we designed that game,
MC Xiao Yang: we had a lot of people test it.
MC Xiao Yang: The cameraman literally threw
MC Xiao Yang: over 30 arrows and didn't land a single one.
MC Xiao Yang: But when Brother Ning stepped up,
MC Xiao Yang: Giants really are just different.
MC Xiao Yang: I think when our players play
MC Xiao Yang: these minigames, they're all amazing.
PD Xiao Qi: It's like they all have
PD Xiao Qi: some kind of superpowers.
PD Shi Yi: Really? Then I...
PD Shi Yi: have an objection about Keyu.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: It's very effective.
PD Xiao Qi: One big impression this year is...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: Bro Ning digests Character Cards in more detail.
PD Xiao Qi: Several times on set, I heard...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: him practically not missing a single word.
PD Xiao Qi: He could accurately recite
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: several large paragraphs from the Character Card.
PD Xiao Qi: When I heard it, I was just...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: I was truly shocked at that moment.
PD Xiao Qi: I would mutter to myself,
"Oh my god,"
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: "Did he memorize all of this?"
PD Xiao Qi: And his ability to act out the story is great.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: He controls his own
PD Xiao Qi: pacing when acting out the story.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: While memorizing
PD Xiao Qi: the details in the card,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: he adds his own performance elements.
PD Xiao Qi: Then on set, with the others,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: he mobilizes everyone's interaction.
PD Xiao Qi: He manages the entire
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: character's pacing very well.
PD Xiao Qi: This truly shocked me at the time.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: It genuinely shocked me a few times.
PD Xiao Qi: Another thing is that he...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: Partly because everyone is very familiar now,
PD Xiao Qi: his ability to make jokes and liven things up
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: has probably gotten stronger too.
PD Xiao Qi: I just feel that he
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: is so at ease this year.
PD Xiao Qi: In terms of making jokes,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: catching jokes,
PD Xiao Qi: catching others' jokes,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: and then creating some hilarious ones himself,
PD Xiao Qi: the frequency is much higher now.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: His ability to deduce the killer is obvious.
PD Xiao Qi: It's definitely gotten stronger.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: The result of the Golden Key
PD Xiao Qi: is a very good proof.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: Another point we've always
PD Xiao Qi: admired about Bro Ning across seasons:
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: he's gotten stronger at it this year too.
PD Xiao Qi: That is his ability to deduce the plot.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: He receives the plot,
PD Xiao Qi: deduces the plot, and predicts the plot.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: He is truly amazing.
PD Xiao Qi: He can always be a prophet.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: He can always be ahead.
PD Xiao Qi: When the plot reaches a certain point,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: he can predict several parts ahead,
PD Xiao Qi: the general direction of the plot,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: and what it will look like.
PD Xiao Qi: His deduction ability is also stronger.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: Lastly, this year,
PD Xiao Qi: there's a more obvious feeling:
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: with Bro Ning around,
PD Xiao Qi: I personally would also feel
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: this sense of great reassurance.
PD Xiao Qi: Because Bro Ning is still that very thorough,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: thoughtful, and warm Bro Ning.
PD Xiao Qi: After we finish recording,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: perhaps waiting to shoot the final
PD Xiao Qi: bits of promotional material,
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: while waiting, he would chat with me.
PD Xiao Qi: He would ask me,
PD Xiao Qi:
"How do you think everyone performed today?"
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
PD Xiao Qi: He would worry and say,
"Would anyone, in any particular part,"
"not have enough to say?"
Then he would also think,
because this year there are constant...
When a Guest Star comes,
he'll always think about
prompting the Guest Star to speak more.
During the third case,
because Bro Ning himself was the killer,
after we finished filming that day,
while shooting promotional materials,
Bro Ning asked me, he said,
"Do you think Sun Qian spoke enough today?"
"During the centralized discussion,"
"was her output sufficient?"
"How was her performance?"
He said he asked this because
during the centralized discussion,
since he was the killer,
he was naturally a bit more nervous.
He was thinking about how to defend himself,
who he should throw under the bus,
and whether he was in danger right now.
He got caught up in his own thoughts of,
"How do I escape?"
and "What should I say now?"
And he was also more nervous than before.
He said that day he kind of forgot
to constantly
prompt the Guest Star to speak.
From this point alone, you can
feel how heartwarming Bro Ning is.
He is truly a very warm person.
Bro Ning also makes sure that in every segment,
he never ruins the fun.
Because this year, the Dining Table added a new design,
which requires swiping a Meal card.
They have to take their own cards
and scramble to swipe them everywhere.
When Bro Ning found out
that this year's Dining Table has Meal cards,
and you have to swipe a card to buy food,
after learning about this design,
he said, "Okay,"
"let me think about"
"how we can make it more fun."
So during the
filming of Theme One,
because Theme One was right before
entering the first Dining Table,
while he was filming that,
he would try to
fight for the chance to swipe the card.
And while filming the Dining Table,
he would also create some funny moments
to encourage everyone to fight for
the atmosphere of controlling the food.
So, for our Let's Start Deduction,
all the guests are actually a group of...
they are a group of people who never ruin the fun.
Bro Ning himself was very engaged and had a great time,
and with this group of younger siblings,
he has become more familiar.
And they would give each other
a vibe of having each other's backs,
which gave me a more reassuring feeling.
For example, during the pilot episode,
he was afraid of the electricity,
so a group of younger siblings went first for him.
He also knew there would be a group of people supporting him.
He also knew that when dancing,
as long as he called for it,
a group of people would dance with him.
And when the lights went out,
there would be a group of people holding onto each other with him,
supporting each other,
and cheering each other on.
The jokes he usually makes
would definitely be picked up by someone.
He's not only a big brother taking care of the younger siblings,
but he's also a Bro Ning who, in front of the younger ones,
can have a lot of fun
and show a very relaxed side of himself.
Everyone on Let's Start Deduction is really such a good sport.
You see, this season, we actually have
some segments that are pretty over-the-top.
Like the Skill Cards.
Right.
Both the names and poses are so embarrassing.
And every time, they still have to act out
the part where the thing appears.
And then Bro Ning would lead everyone
to put on very exaggerated performances.
And the way they acted it out
was just so cute.
Everyone was just the type
who, for any segment designed by the crew,
would try their best to maximize
the comedic effect.
Yeah.
The things you design are effective.
Because they also know that your set design
and other designs took a lot of effort.
Yeah.
Sometimes,
even if we wanted to be cringey,
the players would also try very hard
to embrace the cringe with us.
Yeah.
When seeing them try so hard to create the effect together,
it was still quite touching.
Right.
They were willing to take such over-the-top
designs, and interpret
and act them out.
Like hiding under that camouflage cloth,
they would be very engaged and immersed.
Bro Ning is a very... he...
Because his mind is very active,
so he often
comes up with wild ideas, or says,
"Let's seriously create this effect together."
It's just that every one of our
guests loves to play,
and is very willing to cooperate.
And because there's a group of people who are good sports,
it makes
everyone more willing
to bring up these ideas.
And whatever any of us proposed,
we would all make it happen together.
Having a group of friends who love playing together
also gives them
a greater sense of security with each other.
Because here, no matter what,
someone will always play along with any joke you make.
Right, someone will always back you up.
There's another one also about Bro Ning,
a very heartwarming little detail.
It was during a case when they searched the trash cans,
and it was raining that day.
Yeah.
Our NPCs would prank them,
like blowing air or splashing water on them.
The NPCs were blowing air and splashing water on them.
Bro Ning insisted on braving this prank,
and helped them put all the lids back on.
This is another detail
that makes you instantly feel
he is truly a great person.
Bro Ning would say,
"Let's cover them up,
or they'll get completely soaked."
Actually, a lot of Bro Ning's little details
just make everyone feel so warm and cared for.
Whether it's on camera or off camera,
he's really good to the staff.
Yes.
I feel like Bro Ning treats
the players of Let's Start Deduction
and the staff members as well,
as his own people.
Because I still remember during
the filming of the first season,
it was right around the Dragon Boat Festival.
It was right around the Dragon Boat Festival.
He prepared for every single staff member
those five-color braided bracelets for the festival.
And from the first season up till now,
every winter, actually,
he would send us those Dandong strawberries.
It's thanks to Bro Ning
that we get to eat
the most authentic, genuine ones.
So delicious.
Every year when this season comes,
there's one thing to look forward to,
eating those really delicious strawberries.
Right.
So sweet and tasty.
Really, thank you, Bro Ning.
Yes.
You can also feel that Bro Ning really loves
Let's Start Deduction.
One day, he suddenly mentioned Sis Jin, saying,
saying Sis Jin wasn't very good with chopsticks.
Then Sis Jin was very confused:
"How do you know I can't use chopsticks?"
And then he said,
"I watched that mini-game from the first episode."
He said, "When you were using chopsticks there,
everyone else was picking things up fine,
but you couldn't pick up those glass beads."
I just didn't expect that for this kind of
spin-off promotional material,
which everyone filmed individually,
Bro Ning was actually paying attention to all of it.
He truly loves our show,
Let's Start Deduction.
Many viewers might also be curious
about what Bro Ning's reaction was
when he got his script with only the word "Amnesia."
Was Ningbo Weibu in episode five really a blank script?
How blank was it exactly?
Ningbo Weibu was indeed a blank script.
The extent of it was that he only knew
a little bit of what happened after he woke up.
The amount of information he actually knew
was completely given away during his opening.
Just those few sentences:
that a dead body was lying next to him,
and he couldn't remember anything.
Then he met a servant who told him he was the young master,
named Ningbo Weibu.
The dead person was his adoptive father,
and they came for the Sword Appreciation Convention.
Every one of our Character Cards has a header,
which is an introduction that states,
it states each player's character name and
what relationship that character has with them.
Just some very simple, summarizing information like that.
So how blank was it, to describe it?
I can use the header on Ningbo Weibu's card
to describe it for you.
His header said, "Player, colon, Jin Jing."
Then the character name was a question mark.
There was no relationship to him mentioned,
nor any basic information.
And every player was like, "Player, Zhang Linghe,
character name question mark."
He only knew that the ones
recording with him today were the other five guests.
As for everyone's character names
and their relationships to him,
he knew absolutely no background information at all.
Including the public knowledge that everyone else knew,
he didn't know that either.
It was the most blank script in history.
Everything that happened before he woke up
can be summarized in one word:
Amnesia.
And his reaction to this card was...
Because the details of this card
were checked the day before recording.
And it was also his first time getting
an Amnesia Script where he forgets everything.
Bro Ning just said at the time, "Okay, no problem.
I'll just improvise on set tomorrow."
And he also knew
that from his perspective,
a lot of things would definitely be missing.
Because he's experienced,
he knew that the others' perspectives
would definitely fill in his missing information.
He was also anticipating,
"Tomorrow on set, I should experience
a very rich process
of absorbing new information." He expected that.
So, early on,
as things were revealed step by step,
was he curious
about what kind of character he really was?
Because everyone came up and scolded him,
calling him a traitor
and saying all sorts of things.
When he was first scolded,
he definitely couldn't be sure
whether he used to be a good guy or a bad guy.
When the first person scolded him,
you could tell from his reaction
that he suspected,
"Maybe I really was a bad guy before."
But by the time he was...
slowly scolded...
scolded by the second
or third person, he would...
Because he still has
a very sharp grasp of the plot,
he started guessing
that his identity might have a twist.
He shouldn't be a pure villain.
He probably had some unrevealed stories.
He would make these kinds of guesses.
But he wouldn't ask me,
because he's very experienced.
He knew he wouldn't get
any new information out of me.
Bro Ning is someone who really likes
absorbing things himself,
combining them with what he already has,
and then analyzing them.
He really enjoys the process
of slowly learning and analyzing.
The process is very important to him;
the result might not matter as much.
Whether his analysis was right or wrong,
he had a blast recording that day.
Whether it was starting with a blank slate
and slowly piecing together the information,
or deducing the methods of that case,
throughout that whole day,
he felt he had a lot of fun playing.
Then I'd also like to ask,
when Bro Ning was recording the show,
did anything interesting happen?
One thing I found very interesting,
which wasn't caught on camera,
is that Bro Ning has a magical skill.
A skill I truly find magical.
It might have to do with his great observation skills.
Even though he's so tall,
when he walks around,
he can just spot and pick things up.
Yeah.
There were several times
when it wasn't the only time.
There were several times when he was just walking,
and when I didn't see anything at all,
you'd suddenly see him bend down.
And the thing he picked up
would be something very important.
For example, one day during the recording of Theme 1,
we were transitioning between sets.
It was raining that day,
so we were holding umbrellas,
moving from outdoors to indoors together.
Then, when he walked up
to an iron gate,
he suddenly bent down.
He suddenly picked up
something from the ground.
The rest of us were
just standing there, not registering it.
I was wondering why he suddenly bent down,
or if he had tripped on something.
Then you saw him pick up whatever it was,
and Bro Ning said,
"Whose is this?
Is it a prop or did someone drop it?
Maybe someone dropped it.
Someone dropped their accessory.
I'll ask them about it later."
It was an accessory.
I couldn't see it at all.
And I remember
that last season
Bro Ning also found something.
Yes.
It happened two or three times this season too.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): It happened two or three times this season. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): And it happened last season too. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): It just deepened my impression. LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): I'm truly amazed by this trait of his. LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): Then he took it and went inside,
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): into the set to ask around. DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): And he found the owner right away.
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): It was something someone had been looking for a long time. * DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): It was a very expensive item. DEDUCTION
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): Bro Ning is almost becoming Let's Start Deduction's DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): lost and found office. DEDUCTION
DEDUCTION TONGCHENG TRAVEL
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): This skill, * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): his ability to pick things up, LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): really, over these past few seasons, * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): is always happening. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): It's like he has a KPI to meet. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): It really feels like he does. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): It's just very magical. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): You might think this thing, * LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): is it because he has great observation skills? LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): Possibly, I'd just attribute DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): attribute it to that. LET'S START
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): It shows that Bro Ning LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): is also usually a * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): very attentive person. * DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): Yes, very meticulous. *
Ding Chengxin's PD (Dada): His attention is highly focused. * DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): And he often picks up expensive things. DEDUCTION
MC (Xiao Yang): I remember when Bro Ning was asking DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
MC (Xiao Yang): "Whose is this?" * DEDUCTION
MC (Xiao Yang): "Did someone lose something?" START
MC (Xiao Yang): that staff member screamed out loud. LET'S START DEDUCTION TONGCHENG TRAVEL
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): Right, like a savior descending. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
MC (Xiao Yang): Yeah. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): That phone incident as well. LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): Because it was our staff member, * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): we had an * LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): intern's phone, I think. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): And she also lost it, * LET'S START DEDUCTION
LET'S START DEDUCTION TONGCHENG TRAVEL
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): and he found it. * LET'S START DEDUCTION
MC (Xiao Yang): Is it because tall people have a wider field of vision? LET'S START DEDUCTION
LET'S START DEDUCTION TONGCHENG TRAVEL
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): I don't know. *
DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): His eyesight must be really good. * DEDUCTION
Tongcheng Travel
MC (Xiao Yang) Great eyesight * Start Deduction
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But you wrote him so tall * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Because he's too tall? * Start
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Are his eyes far from the ground? *
Tongcheng Travel
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) I felt just like that Start Deduction
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) Being so tall, he must be Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) So his eyesight must be great * Start
Let's Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
MC (Xiao Yang) Okay, next let's deduce
MC (Xiao Yang) Let's talk about Sis Jin next * Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
MC (Xiao Yang) In the show, you know * Deduction
MC (Xiao Yang) She always makes everyone laugh * Start
Tongcheng Travel
MC (Xiao Yang) But what about her in private? * Start
MC (Xiao Yang) What is she really like? Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
MC (Xiao Yang) Let's invite Sis Lu to share Deduction
Let's Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Actually, off-camera Start Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She's very quiet most of the time * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Rigorous and used to reviewing * Start
Let's Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Sis Jin takes Let's Start Deduction *
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Very seriously * Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She doesn't treat the show Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) As just another gig * Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) But as a piece of art * Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She hopes this show becomes Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) A great piece of work Deduction
Let's Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) On day one at her hotel * Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She was very quiet in private * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She's very strict with work * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Thinking deeply over her Character Card *
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Asking about details very clearly * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Caring deeply about the logic flow * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Let's Start Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Sis Jin's memory is incredibly good * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Every time we review the card Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) I'll let her read it once first * Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) After she's familiar with it * Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) After she's familiar with it Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) After she's familiar with it Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) We'll review it in detail again Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Finally, I will quiz Sis Jin Start Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) On the card's key info from memory * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Like, why did you come here? * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) When did you discover it? * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) What's your murder motive? * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She remembers everything Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Let's Start Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She truly is a rigorous person * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Not just done after recording * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She reviews her performance Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Like during a Season 4 Ep 1 break Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She went back to the RV and asked me
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) From what you saw in the control room
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) How was it? Was it good? Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) The control room was cracking up *
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) The Hui Huozi part was brilliant Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Why did she doubt herself? * Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Later, this question before the second *
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Recording was answered Start Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Yesterday I reviewed the card with her
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Before reviewing the card
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Sis Jin said after the last recording Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She went back and did a review * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She felt she fell short in some parts Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She was very nervous the first time * Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) And couldn't let go in some parts Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) So she felt it might have Start Deduction
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Affected the show's entertainment value *
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) But after the recording was done * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) It actually gave her much confidence *
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) Because everyone vibed so well * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) So she told me * Start Deduction
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She clearly knows that in the show * Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) She has another important role * Start
Tongcheng Travel
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) To be between the Guest Stars and regulars Start
Jin Jing PD (Lulu) The best glue holding them together * Start
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She doesn't just review it personally.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Or care about how well she performed.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): But thinks about the overall direction.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Like how to serve the show.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): How to boost morale and emotional connection.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She cooperates with everyone.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She really loves this show.
MC (Xiaoyang): Right.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): At Starlight Cafe's opening in episode 3...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): You could see Sis Jin was in a new state.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): As the only customer in that episode...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She had to prompt the process...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): While also hyping up the opening vibe.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): It was actually quite difficult.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): It could have easily fallen flat.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): But it was smooth all the way.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
LET'S START DEDUCTION
LET'S START DEDUCTION TONGCHENG TRAVEL
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
LET'S START DEDUCTION
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Also, Sis Jin often...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Switches seamlessly from deducing...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): To acting her heart out the next second.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): What impressed me most was in episode 1...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Sis Jin arguing with NPC An Yi at trial.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): That part was totally improvised by her.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): It wasn't on the Character Card.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): But she performed incredibly well.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Beyond our imagination.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): It was simply an iconic scene.
LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): At Starlight Cafe's opening in episode 3...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): There were many unexpected situations.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Like the part where the cup spilled.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She reacted very quickly on the spot.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She could catch all the jokes.
LET'S START DEDUCTION
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Also, Sis Jin knows internet memes...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Like the back of her hand.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): In her character design for each episode...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): We'd include some interesting memes.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): It required Sis Jin to lead everyone...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): To sing, dance, and interact together.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): I would show her viral internet videos...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): And she knew them all, she'd seen them.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): So our communication was very fast.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She has exceptional comprehension skills.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Because Sis Jin has a director's mindset.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): So every time we go over the script...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Like she already has visuals in her head.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She'd consider how to present the scene.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She takes the text on the Character Card...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): And interprets it very vividly.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Another thing is that Sis Jin might be...
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): The most timid person on the entire show.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She gets scared very easily.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): When the lights go out, she screams.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): She's truly terrified.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Actually, I can relate to her very well.
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Because I'm also very timid.
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): Every time we stand in for blocking...
TONGCHENG TRAVEL
Jin Jing's PD (Lulu): I get scared to death.
Let alone during the recording.
The lighting and vibe are even scarier.
Actually, I'm always worried she'll be terrified.
I often see her getting scared to exhaustion.
She would completely go weak in the knees.
But Sis Jin has never once told me...
"I'm so scared,"
"I can't do this," or things like that.
She's never said it.
Luckily, the bros and little brothers all protect her.
So even though she knows that every episode...
Will have some scary segments,
She never backs down.
For someone who is naturally timid...
And easily frightened,
We have to give Sis Jin a huge thumbs up for this.
I hope Sis Jin can be even braver in season five,
And challenge a Solo Mission.
Another thing is that in Sis Jin's eyes,
she just wants to protect the girls.
Because the guest stars this season are all girls,
so whether in the show or off-camera,
she takes great care of them.
During recording, she gives the guest stars tips.
When taking a break to touch up makeup,
she sits and chats with them,
explaining some rules of the show
and the recording process.
Even though she's a scaredy-cat herself,
when it actually gets scary,
she makes sure to hold the scared guest star's hand,
protecting her
and keeping her from being left alone.
Right.
Sis Jin also always thinks about
whether the effect is good enough,
and if the vibe on set is fun. She also...
Actually, when guest stars come over,
and some of them are girls,
she constantly mentions the guest stars
to help them blend in with us quickly.
And she really takes care of the guest stars.
It's that kind of girl-to-girl care.
Right.
You can really feel that Sis Jin,
whenever there are guest stars around,
even though she's scared herself,
she still protects others.
In the dark,
like sometimes when the lights go out,
she's actually quite timid,
but she still protects them,
hugging them tightly.
And I think Sis Jin is just...
After participating for several seasons,
even though she's still scared of these segments,
I feel like every season,
she makes more progress than the last.
She tries to push her limits.
Yes.
So, Sis Lu, is there anything else
you want to share with everyone?
I noticed that Sis Jin remembers everyone's
works very clearly.
In the first episode,
there was tangerine candy on the table.
Sis Jin immediately interacted with Bro Zhang, saying,
"I think I've seen this scene before.
Someone and someone."
Bro Zhang smoothly played along and asked, "Want some?"
When everyone was in the cage,
looking for the matching keys via tags,
there was a small tag that said,
"Don't call me bro, call me baby."
Sis Jin immediately said,
"Xiao Ding, it's you!
You said that in your live stream clip!
'Don't call me bro, call me baby.'"
Xiao Ding forgot it himself,
but Sis Jin remembered.
Also, Bro Ning's songs,
Keyu's memes...
There's just so much.
She keeps it all in her head.
She's not doing it for show,
but because they are people she cares about.
When she hears something, she takes it to heart.
It's an instinctive kind of attention.
So, a lot of times on the show,
she can just blurt them out.
Yes.
Yes, Sis Jin is truly
our source of joy, on and off camera.
You can clearly feel that
having Sis Jin around makes
the other guests feel a lot of joy.
She creates a lot of happiness
and spreads it to everyone.
Right, she lightens up the atmosphere.
For example, when guest stars come over,
they don't feel as much pressure.
They can blend in with everyone better.
She makes jokes herself
to help others alleviate
their psychological pressure or burden.
She can build a bridge
so that the guest stars can quickly
blend into our deduction team.
Right, Sis Jin is indeed
the joy bringer of Let's Start Deduction.
Next, some netizens also want to ask
about Sis Jin in this season.
Are there any regrets?
Sis Jin actually has some regrets this season.
She has strong analytical skills,
but the Golden Key always passes her by.
She is very smart
and highly logical.
Her deduction skills are completely on point.
Her analysis of the clues is actually spot on.
But when it comes to the final vote,
she gets extremely conflicted.
She probably doesn't want to be influenced by outside factors,
but she's actually very easily fooled.
The main reason for this might be
that she is highly empathetic.
As long as someone sincerely tells her it wasn't them,
she becomes very unsure.
She is super hesitant every time she votes.
Sometimes she actually picks the right one.
The name on that board
is already written correctly.
But then she rethinks and doubts herself,
crosses it out to rewrite it,
and ends up voting wrong.
All right, thanks to Sis Lu for sharing.
Now let's hand the mic over
to Bro Zhang's PD, Weiwei.
Bro Zhang, well, this season,
you guys can probably feel it too,
apart from improving his deduction skills
and having many brilliant moments,
he also showed a much more relaxed side.
Because he actually mentioned before,
he said coming to Let's Start Deduction
is, in a way,
like a vacation for him.
So he's quite relaxed,
showing many sides of himself on the show
that might contrast sharply with his usual image.
And as Bro Zhang's PD,
working closely with him this season,
I was lucky enough to see more of his
warm and thoughtful side
off-camera.
Since I saw everyone was very curious before
as to why Bro Zhang
on our show
suddenly turned into a huge foodie this season,
just eating a lot,
and every day
constantly eating non-stop.
Literally eating every single day.
As long as he's on screen,
he is eating.
It's very cute.
It really is.
There's actually a reason behind it.
At the time,
because he was filming a drama,
and for that role, he actually
had to match the character's look,
so he lost a ton of weight.
He dieted down so much
that he was probably at his thinnest.
When he later came to film Let's Start Deduction,
he was almost done with that crew.
Back then, Bro Zhang's family gave
his staff a mission,
which was to fatten him up.
As for our Let's Start Deduction production team,
we immediately and voluntarily joined in
on this task of feeding Bro Zhang.
From then on, basically in every space
that could hold food, we'd put food.
Whether it was snacks,
or bread,
or all kinds of delicious food
on the Dining Table,
we would put out as much as possible.
And sometimes we'd see that
huge teapot on our show.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And generally inside that teapot
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: is a big bucket of milk tea that everyone loves.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And there's also coffee.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Bro Zhang would sometimes stand next to it
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and mix a coffee-milk tea blend for everyone.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He eats, but he also feeds everyone else.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So later on, basically in every space,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: his most important task apart from Evidence Search
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: was to look around
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and see what good food was there.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: If he couldn't find any, he'd write "send some" on paper.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: You ruined my punchline.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I was going to share this story later.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I just felt really happy too.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: That we were able to, you know,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: make him enjoy the food in the show, actually
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: we also felt very happy.
MC Xiaoyang: Right.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Yeah.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So for the game design, we specially
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: designed some food challenges.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like in the fifth case, there was...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: some "One-bite Bun" challenge.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And there was a pancake house.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: We just hoped he could play
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and eat at the same time.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: Naturally blending into it.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Right.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like during the ninth case,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: we actually had weird-flavored food.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: But he still ate it happily.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Because it had fish mint, which he loves.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So I wasn't worried at all.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then he was the only one...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: while everyone else felt
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: the food tasted awful.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He ate the fish mint by himself,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: enjoying it so much.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then during the fifth case,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: didn't we have that "One-bite Bun"?
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Since that was his product placement,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I showed him in advance
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: what the actor for the placement looked like.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then Bro Zhang recognized her himself.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He said she's a famous chef,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and her food is delicious.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So when he entered the Ghost Market,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he kept asking,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "Where is that stall?"
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I heard him saying in the mic,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "Why haven't I found that product placement stand yet?"
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then, after he went in and saw it,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he said, "This must be delicious."
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: It was delicious, and he felt like...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He said, "This isn't a challenge for me."
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "It's a reward." Right.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: It really was very delicious.
MC Xiaoyang: Yeah.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Exactly.
MC Xiaoyang: Every time he arrives at a scene,
MC Xiaoyang: Bro Zhang immediately
MC Xiaoyang: rushes toward the snacks.
MC Xiaoyang: Then, holding a bunch of snacks,
MC Xiaoyang: he starts the evidence search.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Yes, yes, yes.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Actually, Bro Zhang also feeds us a lot.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Off-camera, he constantly brings food for the directors.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: For example, many friends
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: probably saw it on our official Weibo.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: For our final recording,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: since it was close to Wuxi,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he fed us
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: lots and lots of delicious peaches.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: They were big and sweet.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Also, he brought us a lot of other good food.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: For instance, during the first recording,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he gave us a lot of instant noodles.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like, a lot of ramen.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And basically, at that time,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: because we often worked overtime,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: when working late, we essentially
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: survived on his ramen.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: Sometimes we worked late into the night
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: when there was no delivery available.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Right.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: The ramen Bro Zhang gave us
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: was the most convenient option, and
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Right.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: we could eat it right away.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Yeah, and there were so many flavors.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: Exactly, exactly.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Also, he frequently ordered milk tea for us.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So basically, in various regions...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Because Let's Start Deduction
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: films in different locations,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: we got to drink
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: all the delicious local milk teas.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Also, sometimes we might...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: PDs review the cards in the morning
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: or go over today's
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: segments with him.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And he would bring us treats then too.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like bringing me lots of coffee
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: or milk tea.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Whenever we met with his team,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: we'd get to drink great milk tea.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Sometimes he'd worry you hadn't eaten breakfast,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and his team
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: would even cook dumplings for you.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: It felt really heartwarming.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Because they are just so nice.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Bro Zhang and his team are all people
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: who truly care about the staff's feelings.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So it really felt like
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: the show team and Bro Zhang had a
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: mutual feeding kind of relationship.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Another thing about Bro Zhang
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: is that this season,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he's gotten much closer
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: with his friends and the rest of the cast.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So he's much more relaxed now.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: When joking around with everyone,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he cares less and less about his image.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Sometimes we even think
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he's become this cute little demon child.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: There was one time, which you
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: probably saw in the broadcast...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Once, after he went inside,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he was doing an evidence search in a room.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: While searching, he found
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: a very important clue.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: It said that this clue
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: allowed him to communicate with the outside,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: an exchange of information.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He immediately started writing furiously.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And after writing for a while,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: we received a message saying,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "Please send some food and drinks in."
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And most importantly, that clue...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: was actually the kind meant for a pencil rubbing,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and then you'd be able to see
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: more information inside.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And so, everyone
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: found out that our important clue
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: was accidentally ruined by him.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: Used up as scratch paper.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Right, used up as scratch paper.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then he felt really embarrassed himself,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: because he was also a bit guilty.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And later on, we were
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: laughing so hard in the control room.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: We just found it hilarious, and then
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: after wrapping up, I went out and told him...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I said, "You were so cute just now."
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "But did you forget
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: you have a Copy Card?"
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "Like, you could have restored this clue."
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He was so frustrated that he had
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: forgotten he had this card.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And he also has this mischievous side.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like, this season, he actually
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: seems more like an edgy teenager.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: It feels like turning 28 means subtracting 18.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: On set, basically,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: whenever he sees any fun props,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he wants to get his hands on them.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like the cleaning cart in Case One,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and all sorts of other things like that.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Like some little toys we might have placed around,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he'd want to play with them all.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And then during the fifth case,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: there was that, um, double-sword staff.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And he really liked it himself.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: When he saw it, he said, "So cool!"
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And he couldn't put it down.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then, because our show has
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: those blackout segments during filming,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and the blackout segments are actually...
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: if there are any lighting effects,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: the effect might be somewhat compromised.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Before recording, seeing how much he liked it,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I told him,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: "Later on,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: if you are in a relatively
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: dark environment, don't take it out to play."
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: At first, he joked with me,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: saying, "Then I'll use it to fight the NPC."
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: But during the actual recording, he knew.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He'd quietly leave the sword outside.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He purposely didn't bring it in.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Because he'd still be aware
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: that there was a blackout segment ahead.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He deliberately wouldn't bring it in.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So even though he seems to
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: sometimes be very playful verbally,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and likes to do fun things
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: to make everyone laugh,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he is actually quite considerate of
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: the show's overall effect,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and thinks about the content.
Yeah.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And it's the same with the other guys.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Sometimes he really likes to tease everyone.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: For example, once with Little Ding,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he jokingly teased him like this.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He said, "If you're the killer today,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I'm going to tell you ghost stories."
Tongcheng Travel
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: I remember, I remember.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: It was very cute.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He would also often say
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he must spice things up for Little Ding.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: But he was actually just playing around.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: During those blackout segments,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: he was actually the one
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: who'd quickly protect Little Ding.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And it was the same during the Solo Mission.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: That time, wasn't Little Ding alone
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: doing the Solo Mission outside?
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He kept watching from inside the cage,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: worried Little Ding would be too scared
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: or something like that.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And he kept talking to him.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Then finally, he just
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: went out to help him finish it together.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: So sometimes he is kind of...
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: having a sharp tongue but a soft heart.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: And he often teases Sis Jin too.
Yeah.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: As you'll also see in the main feature,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: but during the fourth case,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: when choosing one of two, he gave
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: a reason that I found very heartwarming.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He felt Sis Jin hadn't gotten a Golden Key either,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: so even if he lost, he wouldn't mind.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: I just feel that in his heart,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: these older brothers and sisters,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: as well as the younger brothers,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: on one hand, they treat him very well,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: so he also wants to treat them well
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: and bring warmth to everyone.
Tongcheng Travel
MC Xiaoyang: He always just verbally teases
MC Xiaoyang: Sis Jin about not getting the Golden Key,
Tongcheng Travel
MC Xiaoyang: but he's actually quite considerate sometimes.
PD Weiwei: I think Bro Zhang this season,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: has actually improved even more in deduction.
PD Weiwei: You'll see it in the main episodes as well.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: Even though he looks very relaxed,
PD Weiwei: many times he just silently
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: solves some of the puzzles,
PD Weiwei: and silently
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: solves some of the tricks too.
PD Weiwei: Also, when reviewing cards privately,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: you'll find he really pays attention to details.
PD Weiwei: Actually, when we write the Character Cards,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: we hide a lot of information in them.
PD Weiwei: And sometimes, because we
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: have pacing requirements to trigger,
PD Weiwei: when writing the Character Cards,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: we use some narrative tricks.
PD Weiwei: It won't be stated so explicitly.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: It requires you to maybe,
PD Weiwei: while reading carefully,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: discover that the details and
PD Weiwei: information inside are very, very useful,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: and then say it out loud.
PD Weiwei: But Bro Zhang always very quickly,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: maybe a step ahead, realizes
PD Weiwei: the information inside is very important.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: For example, the first time,
PD Weiwei: with that killer card.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: Don't both factions have
PD Weiwei: clues and info to identify teammates
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: in their own Character Cards?
PD Weiwei: And at that time, in his Character Card,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: this information was written
PD Weiwei: in two completely different places.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: And when he was reading his card,
PD Weiwei: he discovered,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: "Is this information actually saying
PD Weiwei: that I might be contacting my teammate
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: at this specific time, or something like that?"
PD Weiwei: He just manages to find these details.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: Also, during the third episode,
PD Weiwei: at that time it was basically a situation
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: where everyone thought they were the killer.
PD Weiwei: But the moment he got his card,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: he started to think,
PD Weiwei: "Is it possible I'm not the real killer today?"
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: But because at the time we
PD Weiwei: had pacing requirements to trigger,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: we'd vaguely try to cover it up.
PD Weiwei: But he would actually, based on
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: many detailed clues inside,
PD Weiwei: deduce this step very early on.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: Then during the fifth episode,
PD Weiwei: because he was the Lead Detective that episode,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: he might have had a lot of info and clues,
PD Weiwei: because as an
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: eyewitness, he had to see a crime scene.
PD Weiwei: Well, at that time, because we had pacing triggers,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: we actually wrote it with more narrative tricks.
PD Weiwei: Because he was an eyewitness,
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: we wanted him to truly believe
PD Weiwei: Ningbo Weibu was actually killed.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: So we used a lot of narrative tricks
PD Weiwei: to write the information he witnessed.
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: But the moment he read the script,
PD Weiwei: he began to suspect
Tongcheng Travel
PD Weiwei: whether Ningbo Weibu was really...
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: Was he dead or what?
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: He would have some guesses.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: Maybe when more clues are deduced later,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: and he realizes Ningbo Weibu might be a good guy,
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: he would immediately realize that
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: what's written on his Character Card
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: is actually problematic.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: Because he actually said at the time,
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: he said Ningbo Weibu's face couldn't be seen.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: This is actually a point of deduction.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: In the Character Card, we only
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: wrote that Ningbo Weibu was carried over a shoulder.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: But he would deduce and expand on it, thinking,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: "When being carried like that, doesn't it mean
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: most of the time, he must be facing down?"
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: Right.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: So he would deduce from this point,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: "then maybe the person I saw at the time
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: was no longer Ningbo Weibu himself."
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: So actually, there's a lot...
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: I mean, maybe this season,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: when Bro Zhang reads the script,
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: it's like when we usually play a murder mystery,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: a lot of information needs to be pieced together.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: But this season, I feel Bro Zhang
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: got a bit better at deduction.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: He would pick out a lot of details,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: and then, at moments
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: when you are very surprised,
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: he would speak up a step ahead
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: and deduce this thing.
Yeah.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: This season, I'm very happy to see
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: a much more relaxed side of Bro Zhang.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: I also feel that this relaxed
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: side might also mean
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: he was quite enjoying the recording.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: And we also saw
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: many very warm sides of Bro Zhang.
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: So thank you very much to him for being able to
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: stand in the staff's shoes so often
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: and think about a lot of things for us.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: I also feel that people becoming fans of Bro Zhang
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: is a very natural thing to happen.
Tongcheng Travel
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: Because he really is a very worthy
Zhang Linghe's PD Weiwei: and very warm person.
Yeah.
MC Xiaoyang: Indeed.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Agreed.
MC Xiaoyang: Agreed.
Liu Yuning's PD Xiaoqi: Yes.
MC Xiaoyang: I mean, becoming a fan of Bro Zhang is indeed
MC Xiaoyang: a very easy thing to do. And also,
MC Xiaoyang: thank you, Bro Zhang, for treating Let's Start Deduction as a
MC Xiaoyang: journey where you can relax
MC Xiaoyang: but also one worth fully engaging in.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Just seeing Bro Zhang able to
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: eat snacks so casually on the show,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: it really makes you feel like he treats
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: this place as a very safe
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: and familiar environment.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: And we felt especially happy when we saw that too.
MC Xiaoyang: Yes.
MC Xiaoyang: Since Bro Zhang was also on the show this season,
and ate so many snacks,
the audience really wants to know
which one is his favorite.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: That question, actually,
our production team is also very curious about it.
Because we really hope to
prepare more delicious food for him.
So we asked Bro Zhang, and he said,
"I like all of them."
He said adults don't make choices.
He said he eats everything, sweet, sour, bitter, or spicy.
He just loves eating them all.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi: We also asked if they had anything
they wanted to eat next season,
so we could arrange it in advance.
And Bro Zhang also said
he wanted food from everywhere.
All different cuisines,
all flavors, snacks, and proper meals,
he wants them all.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He seeks balanced nutrition and loves eating it all.
He feels that if there are
more varieties in flavor,
he'd be happier.
Mm-hmm.
MC Xiaoyang: Okay, earlier this year Bro Zhang said his goal
was to become the Golden Key King.
Mm-hmm.
MC Xiaoyang: If he didn't get it,
would he be a bit disappointed?
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: Even though Bro Zhang says
he wants to be the Golden Key King,
that's actually just him
letting his inner teenager out,
mostly just joking around.
Because in reality,
you'd feel that he is completely
unbothered by winning or losing.
Because maybe to him,
the process of filming Let's Start Deduction,
like the deduction process,
or experiencing the side quest stories,
is much more interesting to him.
As for the results,
it's actually hard for his mood
to be affected by the game's results.
Plus, he's often the type
who forgets everything right after filming.
Like the first case, for example,
I remember when we watched it together,
he even asked,
"Who was the killer in this case again?"
And so,
because he has such a good mindset,
he feels that
"When filming an episode,
it's not like I absolutely must
win the Golden Key or anything."
Right, so that just shows
his really positive mindset.
That's why he's so relaxed in any role,
while still being fully engaged.
Because he doesn't really care
about whether he'll win
or lose this thing.
He's probably thinking more about
whether this place is fun or not.
"I want to explore it."
He has a lot of curiosity.
MC Xiaoyang: Yes, we can definitely feel that.
Every time, Bro Zhang really enjoys the process.
He really isn't an overly competitive person.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei: He probably has zero competitiveness.
PD Weiwei: Every time he comes out after the results,
PD Weiwei: he's always very happy.
PD Weiwei: Regardless of winning or losing,
PD Weiwei: he's still smiling there.
PD Xiao Qi: Capybara.
MC Xiao Yang: Next, we're going to talk about
MC Xiao Yang: a player who newly joined this season,
MC Xiao Yang: but blended in very quickly.
MC Xiao Yang: Let's talk about Xiao Ding.
MC Xiao Yang: Dada, what do you have to share with us?
PD Dada: Well, as this season aired,
PD Dada: actually, everyone has seen on camera
PD Dada: many different sides of Xiao Ding.
PD Dada: Like, he's smart and quick to react,
PD Dada: and his deduction skills are quite good.
PD Dada: He's also very competitive.
PD Dada: But because of my work,
PD Dada: I saw more than everyone else.
PD Dada: That is him off-camera.
PD Dada: Some things are actually very small.
PD Dada: They are so small that they didn't even
PD Dada: make it into the final cut.
PD Dada: I even think that
PD Dada: he might not remember them himself.
PD Dada: But after this season's filming ended,
PD Dada: when I look back at
PD Dada: the time I spent
PD Dada: working with him,
PD Dada: what left a deep impression on me
PD Dada: was exactly these details.
PD Dada: I think he's extremely diligent.
PD Dada: And he's diligent even before filming begins.
PD Dada: Because Xiao Ding is a great dancer,
PD Dada: so when we were designing
PD Dada: the plot for the first episode,
PD Dada: we wanted to ask him to
PD Dada: choreograph a dance for An Songqiu Glass Factory.
PD Dada: After he found out about this,
PD Dada: he started brainstorming very early on.
PD Dada: He researched how to choreograph this dance
PD Dada: to better fit the plot,
PD Dada: and also present it better on the show.
PD Dada: Actually, the dance segment
PD Dada: that everyone saw in the end
PD Dada: was just a small part of the show.
PD Dada: It wasn't very long either.
PD Dada: But he didn't dismiss it as a small task
PD Dada: and casually finish it.
PD Dada: Instead, he really prepared for it in advance,
PD Dada: putting in a lot of time and effort.
PD Dada: Every time Xiao Ding filmed,
PD Dada: he basically arrived in Changsha a day early.
PD Dada: So on the night before filming,
PD Dada: I would go over his Character Card with him.
PD Dada: When I first met him,
PD Dada: I prepared for him
PD Dada: a quick starter guide.
PD Dada: It included some show rules,
PD Dada: the filming process,
PD Dada: and some terms that everyone
PD Dada: frequently uses during deduction.
PD Dada: Well, as a new player,
PD Dada: he picked it up very quickly.
PD Dada: For many things, you just tell him once
PD Dada: and he understands.
PD Dada: Moreover, going over the card the night before
PD Dada: didn't mean that
PD Dada: the preparation work was over.
PD Dada: Early the next morning while doing makeup,
PD Dada: he would still take out his Character Card
PD Dada: and read it over and over again.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: He wanted to make sure he
remembered the character relationships and story better.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: One time we had back-to-back shoots.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: The whole process was very exhausting.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: By the time we wrapped up and got on the shuttle,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada: it was actually past midnight.
But after he got in the car,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): But after he got in the car,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he still offered to
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): go over tomorrow's cards as well.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): On one hand, I admired his energy.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): On the other hand, I admired his
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): dedication to his work.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Because you could tell
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): that to him,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): professionalism isn't something
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he does just to show off to others.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): It's like a very natural habit for him.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): No matter how late or tired he is,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he'll still think about
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): whether he can do
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): a bit more preparation for tomorrow.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): After every shoot,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): we usually have some
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): promotional materials to film.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Everyone takes turns lining up to shoot.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): So there's some waiting time in between.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Xiao Ding rarely lets that time go to waste.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): He handles some of his own work.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): And when I see him working,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I feel like he knows exactly
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): what he needs to do next.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): He's also great at managing his time.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): He's not only hardworking,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): but also highly efficient.
MC (Xiaoyang): Yeah.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): The second point I want to make is
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): how he cherishes items from his characters.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): After the first shoot ended,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Xiao Ding asked me
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): if I could help him save every Character Card,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): work badge,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): and security ID from each episode.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): And then, after the season wraps,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): give them all to him together.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): On set, these are actually
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): small items that are easily overlooked.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): But he'd make it a point
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): to keep them.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I thought that was quite meticulous
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): and pretty cute.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): For him,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): when an episode finishes filming,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): it's not just wrapping up
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): or being done.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): He'll think about keeping
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): all the character items safe
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): to serve as a memento for his first time
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): experiencing Let's Start Deduction.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): During a break in the first shoot,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I was in the RV helping him sort out the story.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): When we were reviewing the clues,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I was writing the key points down on paper.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Because I couldn't find a suitable spot,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I just rested the paper
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): right on my leg to write.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): After Xiao Ding saw that,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he immediately went to find
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): something hard
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): to put under the paper
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): so it'd be easier for me to write.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): It was actually a very small gesture.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): So small he's probably long forgotten it.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): But I've always remembered this detail.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Because at that time,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he was also preparing for his own shoot.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): And it was his first shoot.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): As a newcomer,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he was preparing for his own work.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): He really needed to focus
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): to memorize such a complex story.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): But even under those circumstances,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he still noticed
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): whether the people around him were comfortable.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I just think he's an incredibly considerate,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): meticulous,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): and very warmhearted person.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Okay, the third point I want to mention is his brain.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) It's like it never stops turning.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) During recording,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) I often get the feeling
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) that he's constantly thinking.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Especially when it comes to finding key clues,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he has a very strong determination.
MC (Xiaoyang) Yes.
MC (Xiaoyang) He says that phrase every episode.
MC (Xiaoyang) "I won't do anything else this episode.
MC (Xiaoyang) I just have to find this key clue."
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) As long as he believes a certain place
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) hides very important information,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he'll search it with the determination of
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) "I must find it today."
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) One episode was outdoors in the rain.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Weren't there dozens of trash cans on set?
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He felt that the trash cans
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) definitely hid this key clue.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) So he carefully searched them one by one.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He didn't give up because there were too many.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) And he doesn't just focus on
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) clues that are obviously right in front of him.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He also always pays attention
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) to what's happening on set.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) One time, everyone was taking a photo together.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Mr. Li Fei,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) after yelling "cheese,"
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) casually mentioned
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) the numbers 315, 314, 567.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Many people might hear these numbers
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) and just let it go.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But after Xiaoding heard it,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he immediately started thinking
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) if these numbers had a special meaning,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) and if a code could be cracked from them.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He felt that these
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) numbers followed a pattern or something.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But they actually didn't.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) It was really just Mr. Li Fei
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) saying some numbers casually.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Then he just kept...
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) After Xiaoding heard it,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he kept repeating these numbers,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) trying to find a pattern.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Moments like this
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) actually happen a lot
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) during recordings.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Even if it's something
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) someone said unintentionally,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he won't let it go easily.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He instinctively thinks,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) "Is this a piece of information?
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Does it relate to the story?
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Can it push the deduction a step further?"
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) There was a time this season
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) when he was just one step away
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) from a key clue.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) That clue was actually hidden very well.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Even right before voting,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he still hadn't given up.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He even asked if we could add...
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) I mean, add an extra round of solo evidence search.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) As a result,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) in Ms. Jin Jing's room,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he just narrowly missed it.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Actually, it's normal not to find a clue.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Because in this deduction game,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) key clues are hidden very well.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) So it's normal not to find them.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But to me,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) what touched me more was something else.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Even though he's been through
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) so many recordings,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) and he fails to find it every time,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he still approaches deduction and those
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) clues, those key clues,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) with his original curiosity and passion.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) To me, it's...
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) I think seeing this determination in him
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) is quite rare.
MC (Xiaoyang) Very determined about key clues.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei) If you're the killer, you'd be nervous.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Right.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) Yeah, I was really nervous back then.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) Because he kept hovering
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) around Ke's sword box,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) I was actually, you know, in the control room,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) getting really nervous.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) Thank goodness Ke said at the time,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) "Stop playing around, come listen to me."
MC (Xiao Yang) And then the two of them later, like, at that...
MC Xiao Yang outside of the recording,
MC Xiao Yang they were still discussing it.
MC Xiao Yang Like, about that specific part,
MC Xiao Yang saying, "Yesterday, I almost...
MC Xiao Yang almost checked your sword box."
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Right.
MC Xiao Yang The next day, he was still reviewing it.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei Still fixated on what was in that sword box.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi It will surely echo.
Zhou Keyu PD Shiyi It will surely echo, right?
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei Mainly because every time,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei after knowing he was so close,
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei he became even more...
All Right.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Exactly.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi Does this count as Xiao Ding's regret?
MC Xiao Yang Yeah.
MC Xiao Yang And then, one time, Bro Ning mentioned
MC Xiao Yang that there might be a key clue in the plants.
MC Xiao Yang Then we saw Keyu and
MC Xiao Yang Xiao Ding just rushing out.
MC Xiao Yang Just hearing about a key clue,
MC Xiao Yang the two of them immediately...
MC Xiao Yang They were just triggered by the keyword.
MC Xiao Yang Because it was just a...
MC Xiao Yang just a plant placed in that set.
MC Xiao Yang But the two of them just went there immediately.
Liu Yuning PD Xiaoqi What you hold in your mind...
MC Xiao Yang What you hold in your mind...
Ding Chengxin PD Dada ...will surely echo.
Zhang Linghe PD Weiwei ...will surely echo next season.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Okay.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada The fourth thing I want to talk about is,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he doesn't seem like a new player at all.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada During Xiao Ding's first recording,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada what he actually faced
Ding Chengxin PD Dada wasn't a simple story.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Our show also features free evidence searching,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada so the order in which clues will be found,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada we can't really determine it in advance.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada So players must promptly
Ding Chengxin PD Dada share their own storylines,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada while also avoiding talking about
Ding Chengxin PD Dada the clues that haven't been triggered yet.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada The clues that haven't been triggered yet.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Like, the first time I sat in the
Ding Chengxin PD Dada control room listening to him tell his story,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada I was actually quite nervous for him.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Because there were several times I thought,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada "Is he about to say too much?"
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Like, or maybe he would
Ding Chengxin PD accidentally talk about...
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Or accidentally talk about
Ding Chengxin PD Dada things that can't be revealed yet.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada But every time, he would stop at
Ding Chengxin PD Dada the most appropriate moment.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada He didn't make any mistakes,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada and he knew exactly when to stop,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada leaving just the right amount of suspense for others.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada So whether it's his pacing in storytelling,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada or his reactions to changes on set,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada in my opinion,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada I feel he doesn't seem at all like a first-time
Ding Chengxin PD Dada new player joining a deduction show.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: And then after the first recording ended,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: there was an exclusive interview.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: When everyone talked about his first time
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: successfully escaping as the killer,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: he showed a somewhat
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: smug yet adorable little expression.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: You could really tell
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: that he truly enjoys deduction
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: and was genuinely happy that he
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: completed such a great challenge on his first try.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Later, when new
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: guest stars joined the show,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Xiao Ding would take the initiative
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: to explain the flow of the show to the guest stars.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: From sitting there listening to my rules when we first met,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: to later being able to help
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: others quickly get into the zone,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: I think his speed of adapting
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: to this show was faster than I imagined.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Next, another point I want to mention
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: is that he takes everything
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: in the show very seriously.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: If you paid attention,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: you should have noticed that Xiao Ding's meal card
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: always has the highest balance among everyone.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Every time he enters a recording scene,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: as soon as he sees the card reader,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: he's almost the first to rush over
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: to top up his meal card.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Even the time when he injured his hand
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: and couldn't move around easily,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: he didn't forget about this.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: This way, when it's time for the Dining Table segment,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: he can very confidently
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: treat everyone to good food.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: I've always found this really interesting,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: because, at the end of the day, the meal card is just
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: a minor element in our show's story world.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: But he would earnestly
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: manage his balance.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: He manages his balance,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: and earnestly makes sure
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: to treat everyone to meals.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: I just feel like he really put himself
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: into what our, our production team
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: created for this game world.
MC Xiaoyang: Yes.
MC Xiaoyang: That's right.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: This season,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: this season,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Xiao Ding's deduction accuracy was quite high.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Sometimes I would also worry
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: whether he might take winning and losing,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: winning and losing, and the outcome too seriously.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: During episode six,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: Xiao Ding was voted out as the killer by everyone.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: I was initially worried about his state of mind.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: I was afraid he'd be a bit down.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: But I didn't expect him to so quickly
Ding Chengxin's PD: adjust his state of mind.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: By the time we recorded episode seven,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: he once again,
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: once again threw himself into it, earnest and happy.
Ding Chengxin's PD Dada: He even started speaking Sichuan dialect on the show.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada I actually really like his
Ding Chengxin PD Dada attitude toward winning and losing.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada When he wins,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he shows a little pride he can't hide.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada When he loses,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he also reviews the game,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada then quickly adjusts himself
Ding Chengxin PD Dada and starts over.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Does he not care about the result?
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Actually, I think he values it a lot
Ding Chengxin PD Dada and is very competitive.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada But one result won't bother him.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada He can still continue
Ding Chengxin PD Dada to enjoy the game.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada I think that's a great ability.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada The next point I want to mention is
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he always notices the people around him.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada During one recording,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada the animal episode,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada the NPCs were suspended on the wall
Ding Chengxin PD Dada to complete their performance.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada It actually took a very long time.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Toward the end,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada the NPCs were struggling to hold on.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Xiao Ding was actually watching them.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Until the NPCs left the set,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he kept watching them
Ding Chengxin PD Dada and sincerely thanked them.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada One time, as I was walking
Ding Chengxin PD Dada and talking to him
Ding Chengxin PD Dada about that day's recording,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada the stuff in my hands
Ding Chengxin PD Dada accidentally fell to the ground.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada He quickly bent down to pick it up.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Plus, during the first recording,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he helped find a pad for my paper.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada Actually, none of these things
Ding Chengxin PD Dada were caught on camera,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada but it's exactly these moments
Ding Chengxin PD Dada that showed me the real Xiao Ding.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada When he's deducing,
Ding Chengxin PD Dada he persistently looks for hidden clues.
Ding Chengxin PD Dada In real life,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): He can also
notice some very small details.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): It could be a piece of paper that's hard to write on,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): or something that suddenly fell to the ground,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): or it could be an NPC who has
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): been working hard for a long time.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): His reactions are very fast,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): and he's very attentive.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): A lot of his care isn't something he thinks about
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): and deliberately shows.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): It's just very natural,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): happening subconsciously.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Working with Little Ding this season,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): I often get this feeling.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): It's that his intelligence and abilities
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): are very easily noticed by everyone,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): because all of this is directly
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): shown in the main episodes.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): But after actually working together,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): you'll realize
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): that his dedication
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): isn't just for the cameras.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): His thoughtfulness
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): isn't only shown during those
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): highly important or formal moments.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): There are also many unbroadcasted details.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): These details might be very small,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): so small that if placed into this
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): three to four months of filming,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): they're easily overlooked.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): But it's exactly because of these little things
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): that I'm assured time and time again
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): the person everyone likes is truly wonderful.
MC (Xiaoyang): Yes.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): Plus, Little Ding was great at playing along his first time here.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): Like, he immediately and perfectly
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): played along with Auntie Pai's act.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): And it was probably
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): the most dramatic and over-the-top scene in Let's Start Deduction.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): We didn't necessarily have scenes like that before.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): He was a new player,
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): and they threw that at him right from the start.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): And then, moreover,
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): he was actually the killer in that case.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): Then Auntie Pai came up and said,
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): "You did this and that," smearing him so badly.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei): It's amazing how he withstood the pressure.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): Including when he was spinning around with Sis Jin,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada): he really has great mental fortitude.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): Earlier, during the filming of the first episode,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): it was when Little Ding
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): had just started filming.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): I noticed a really interesting thing about him,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): something very down-to-earth.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): He really likes eating blueberries.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): And the first time he was eating blueberries,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): he had actually eaten so many that his lips
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): were already stained with blueberry juice.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): Then he held up the blueberries to Keyu and asked,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): "Do you want some?"
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): And then he said to Bro Ning,
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): He's just very enthusiastic about sharing
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): his favorite foods with everyone.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): I think it's just...
MC (Xiaoyang): Very cute.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi): Right, it's a very cute trait.
MC (Xiaoyang): Actually, many viewers are also curious.
MC (Xiao Yang) Every time Xiao Ding
MC (Xiao Yang) is just one step away from the key clue,
MC (Xiao Yang) how does he feel about it?
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) I think he must feel a mix of regret
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) and a bit of reluctance to admit defeat.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Because sometimes,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) the truth is clearly right in front of him.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He's physically very close to it.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But he always just misses it at the last second.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) I guess he might be thinking,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) "Why didn't I take one more look?"
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) I feel like he probably thinks that way.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But given Xiao Ding's personality,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) this regret quickly turns into motivation.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He would silently swear to himself,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) "Next time, I must grasp the key clue."
MC (Xiao Yang) Many viewers also want to know,
MC (Xiao Yang) when Xiao Ding is the killer,
MC (Xiao Yang) does he get quite nervous?
MC (Xiao Yang) Because seeing him as the killer for the first time,
MC (Xiao Yang) he actually seemed very at ease.
Ding Chengxin PD He gets nervous, because I believe
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) every player, when acting as the killer,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) gets nervous to some extent.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) So in my eyes,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) he tries to hide his true reactions.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) And he also quietly observes
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) everyone's deduction direction.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) But Xiao Ding reacts very quickly on the spot.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) The more critical the moment is,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) the more he can keep his cool.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) He might look nonchalant on the surface,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) but in reality, his brain might be
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) working overtime, thinking,
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) "Did they find out?"
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) "Should I change the subject?"
MC (Xiao Yang) Xiao Ding's cleverness and his deduction highlights
MC (Xiao Yang) are obvious to everyone on the show.
MC (Xiao Yang) But many small things in everyday life
MC (Xiao Yang) also show us his earnestness, thoughtfulness,
MC (Xiao Yang) and subconscious kindness.
MC (Xiao Yang) Coming to Let's Start Deduction for the first time,
MC (Xiao Yang) he earnestly cherishes the people here
MC (Xiao Yang) and every experience.
MC (Xiao Yang) Next, let's talk about
MC (Xiao Yang) someone who has been with Let's Start Deduction for four seasons,
MC (Xiao Yang) who has been with Let's Start Deduction for four seasons,
MC (Xiao Yang) Little brother Keyu, who acts more like a bro this season.
Liu Yuning's PD (Xiao Qi): The little brother has grown up.
MC (Xiao Yang): The little brother has grown up.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): And working with him this season,
both on and off-camera,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): I feel like he has a lot of very
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): interesting points of contrast.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Many things, seen individually during the shoot,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): are just little details like everyone just mentioned.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): But they are just like puzzle pieces.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): When you put them together, they form a very
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): specific and vivid Zhou Keyu.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): So I feel like...
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): I'll just use a puzzle-like approach
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): to put this Zhou Keyu together.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): For example, during the voting in the first case,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): didn't Keyu vote for Xiao Ding?
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): And later, when the shoot wrapped up,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): he told me
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): that Xiao Ding's demeanor as the killer
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): was a lot like himself in the first season.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): I thought his observation was fascinating.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): First, it shows that Keyu and Xiao Ding
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): are very close in private.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Only then would you know
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): what his different states look like.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Also, on set, we often
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): see Keyu and Xiao Ding
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): huddling together to discuss the game
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): or discuss the plot. And then,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): secondly, his experience in the first season is actually
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): a personal memory that belongs to little brother Keyu.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Now in this season,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): he can use that past experience to observe
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): and understand a new player and guest.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): He didn't just think Xiao Ding was a bit suspicious,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): but he recognized Xiao Ding's expression and state
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): of trying to hide a secret well.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): What I gathered is that he's very observant.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Because he himself was also once
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): very nervous when he got the killer card.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): So he could understand
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): so he could understand
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Xiao Ding's unnatural behavior.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): My impression is that his past experiences
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): left him with more than just deduction skills,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): but also some
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): observation skills
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): and aspects like that.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): The second point is,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): during the shoot of the first theme,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): wasn't our little brother playing An Ke?
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): In the story, Jin Xiangyu accused An Ke
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): of hooking up with her in the past.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Right?
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): And An Ke's reaction at the time,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): during the recording, was,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): "I don't remember."
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Then it turned out, later on,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): when the storyline was revealed,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): little brother found out An Ke really did that.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): Later, during the shoot, he even
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): explained it to me very earnestly.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): He said that when reading his Character Card,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): he only saw one line:
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): "A charming ladies' man in his youth,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): many women threw themselves at him,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): and he never turned them down."
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): He always thought this line
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): was just used to introduce the character's personality,
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): or to provide background information.
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): He didn't expect it to actually correspond to
Zhou Keyu's PD (Shiyi): a very specific experience in the story.
After hearing that, I felt this reaction
was very fitting for An Ke himself.
He wasn't intentionally denying it;
he truly didn't remember.
So I found it quite amazing at the time
that An Ke and Keyu reached
a very unexpected harmony in that moment.
An Ke forgot his own story, and
little brother believed that line
was just a background introduction,
and missed this little detail we deliberately
hid in the Character Card.
A narrative trick.
And by season four, our little brother actually
rarely let anything slip by easily,
especially clues in the Character Cards.
But occasionally, he still got tricked
by this kind of subtle writing...
tricked completely.
It was also really funny on set.
As a PD,
I feel that this kind of
back-and-forth is quite interesting.
I would try to find ways
to hide information in the Character Cards
to see if the players will spot it.
Most of the time,
our little brother manages to find it.
But there was that one time,
An Ke himself didn't remember,
and Zhou Keyu didn't expect it either.
So I've remembered this iconic scene for a long time.
Because of this, in the control room,
everyone laughed so hard.
It was after a certain recording,
little brother Keyu actually made a wish.
He said he hoped he could get
a teenage genius script.
That's why we had Episode 5,
which is Ke Zhouqiujian's original story.
Our little brother really loves Ke Zhouqiujian's story.
On the surface, this story actually
gives off the vibe of a young hero.
But the character's undertone is quite tragic.
This character is always searching for answers,
and he carries some things
that he can't easily let go of.
So when he first read the Character Card,
he resonated a bit with this character.
He didn't just think the character looked cool
or the story was interesting.
He truly understood the emotions
that Ke Zhouqiujian hid beneath his surface.
So later, after getting on set,
on one hand, he naturally showed
the passionate, dramatic side of this character,
and on the other, he also grasped the
deeper and heavier parts of him.
Seeing him love this character so much,
I also felt that Ke Zhouqiujian truly
found the perfect actor to play him.
Friends who enjoy this story can also
go watch Episode 5's case reconstruction.
Master and junior disciple.
Yes, exactly.
You can check out Episode 5's case reconstruction.
It's very exciting.
It's also Ningbo Weibu and Ke Zhouqiujian's
PD's favorite case reconstruction.
After getting on set and receiving the prop sword,
he was practically glued to that sword.
He had to take it wherever he went.
While others were looking for clues on set,
he would casually carry his sword along.
If he changed locations,
and the sword was left in the previous set,
he would run back, grab the sword,
and take it to the next set.
It was also during that theme story,
Ke Zhouqiujian was the killer of that episode.
During a recording break,
I discussed the plot with him outside the inn.
We were figuring out how to clear his suspicion
and lower everyone's alertness.
As luck would have it,
Sis Jin was not far away.
Normally at a time like this,
we should logically be keeping our voices down.
But I didn't expect
that Keyu would suddenly raise his voice.
He started discussing the plot with me very loudly.
Then I reminded him,
telling him to keep his voice down,
saying that walls have ears here.
Sis Jin is right next to us.
Unexpectedly, he didn't stop.
Instead, he kept winking at me,
signaling me to play along and keep acting.
That was when I finally realized
he was intentionally saying it for Sis Jin to hear.
And so, we went from
a normal plot discussion
to suddenly having a loud conspiracy.
The two of us just seriously
continued chatting in front of Jin Jing.
I don't know if Jin Jing believed it in the end.
Anyway, little brother acted so well he convinced himself.
At the time, besides finding it funny,
I also felt he was truly,
completely willing to immerse in the story.
He didn't just earnestly try to clear his name;
when he suddenly had an idea,
he would immediately say,
"Let's give it a try."
As for whether
he managed to fool Jin Jing or not,
it wasn't as interesting as the process itself.
And then, uh, just like everyone
was talking about the meal card earlier...
Actually, after the first recording
of the Dining Table ended,
Keyu confidently declared that
next time, he would work hard
to get first place in meal card points.
But in the new round of recording,
which was the second recording...
Right at the very beginning,
he spilled coffee all over his pants.
That was the cafe theme.
Right, his passion for getting points
was instantly extinguished by that coffee.
He accepted all these things very quickly.
He said he could
go without a meal card.
He'd just leech off Bro Ning and Little Ding's meal cards.
It's like he just gets along
with everyone like a family.
From resolving to be first in points
to accepting he didn't even have a meal card,
the whole process was incredibly fast.
As for getting first in meal cards,
we can only see if next season he can
actually keep his meal card safe first.
Was his meal card stolen?
It got picked up.
It's a whole cycle.
It's a cycle, basically.
Little Ding picked up Keyu's meal card.
Then Keyu picked up Linghe's meal card.
And both of them,
in the second round, really wanted meal cards.
Yeah, in the second round,
when Bro Zhang first saw
that card swipe machine,
he rushed over and swiped,
only to realize he took out a key.
Then he got super deflated
and was like, "My meal card...
you lost it!"
And then he later
found out Keyu had picked it up.
And Keyu also that same time...
Right, that's when he realized his own
meal card was with Little Ding.
That's when we got that,
that "Please, bro,
let your little brother have it" moment, right?
It was around that time.
A chain reaction, anyway.
After that, both of them started on
the path of leeching off everyone's meals.
So going back to when
we were recording in Changsha,
little brother Keyu really wanted Hunan cuisine.
The staff tried to tell him it was too spicy.
We suggested not eating it.
Then he said,
he said everyone was too weak.
"What's so spicy about Hunan food?"
Then he started stuffing food in his mouth,
using his actual actions
to prove he could handle spicy food.
The result was that by that afternoon,
he got an upset stomach.
He got an upset stomach.
Though he didn't admit defeat verbally,
his stomach voiced some different opinions.
And since we had to keep recording,
his management team and I
were waiting outside the restroom.
And while waiting, the two of us,
we reached a consensus with his team,
saying we absolutely must not order
such spicy food for our little brother again.
From now on, he eats light meals on set.
But as for the next time
he encounters Hunan cuisine,
will he tell everyone he's too weak again?
That's hard to say.
Actually, these things aren't
important plot points during filming.
As Dada just said,
they won't be edited into the show.
But they make the guy in front of the camera,
the Zhou Keyu who's more like a bro, more tangible.
Working with Keyu this season,
I often get this feeling.
That is, his deduction skills and on-site performance
are very easy for everyone to see.
But because these things,
because they all appear directly in the show.
They also show up
in his judgment of clues,
his sorting of the story,
and in every single vote.
But working closely together,
you'll find that he has a lot of,
like I said before,
really interesting contrasts.
Even when he's very tired, he will
steadily shoulder the Lead Detective's duties.
And in the third case,
just because of a single petal,
he sent himself straight to the suspect seat.
Then, he wanted the genius boy script,
and he would genuinely be happy for ages
over a prop knife given to him.
So through our cooperation this season,
what I saw was a
Zhou Keyu who's more willing to step up,
and more willing to take on responsibilities.
To me, this kind of growth
didn't turn him into someone who is very,
always staying calm,
and someone who never makes mistakes.
Instead, he's still very straightforward.
Occasionally, he gets confused,
and sometimes gets fooled by the clues in the story.
But I actually think this is
a really good thing.
Because being serious and reliable doesn't mean
you have to become totally stern.
Taking care of others doesn't mean you have to
hide your own panic and cuteness.
This season, just like everyone says,
he's starting to look like a bro,
but at the same time, he's still that
little brother Keyu everyone is so familiar with.
He's grown up, but hasn't become boring.
So this season, all these puzzle pieces formed
a very real Zhou Keyu in my eyes.
Now, he's a reliable and fun little brother.
I have to say,
he personally used his own restoration card
to restore the puppet suit on him.
It restored a clue that pointed
directly to him alone,
which was that flower.
That was also something we had never done before,
making something point so directly,
putting the pressure on one specific person.
At the time, everyone mistakenly thought...
I mean, the guests inside mistakenly thought,
"Did someone accidentally bring out
that key piece of information?" And then,
the little brother definitely felt at the time,
yeah, he really felt at the time
that his key clue...
He really felt like the case was closed.
"Everyone can just vote now."
"I'm totally screwed."
But actually, at that time,
he handled the pressure quite well.
Better than I imagined.
He dealt with the pressure really well back then.
I think that's a really impressive point, too.
I feel like the little brother this season
has freed his true nature a bit more.
It's probably also because they're getting closer,
and much more relaxed around each other.
Yeah, and the little brother this season also had
a lot of those more childish moments.
For example, that "please, bro" moment.
And he'll also, on his own,
like, for example, when he finds out,
like when he finds out his identity
is much higher in seniority than Linghe's,
he'll unconsciously, you know, start smiling.
Very smug.
Yeah, it's just this kind of boyish...
"Whose good boy is this?"
Just that kind of vibe.
They really like,
really like suddenly getting...
They just grabbed our props and started fighting with them.
Don't even know what they were fighting about.
They really enjoy it.
Everyone really enjoys
this "super seniority" thing.
Yes, they really enjoy it.
Next question, about little brother.
When he got the puppy identity,
what was his reaction?
Actually, little brother probably saw the costume first,
before he saw his Character Card.
So when the stylist brought out
the dog ears and tail,
he already started having
some doubts about his identity.
Then I told him that this time
it was a Crazy Animal Party theme,
and he was cosplaying a Cockapoo.
It's a breed of small dog.
His first reaction was to object.
He said, "Why do I look like a puppy?"
And right after he said that,
pretty much all the staff
present answered him together,
"You ARE a puppy!"
So the situation at that time was,
little brother very, very seriously brought up
his point that he didn't look like a puppy,
and was collectively refuted by all the staff.
In the end, he could only take his
confusion
and accept his puppy identity.
Did he resist?
Didn't he say he wanted to milk the loyal dog trope?
He didn't resist.
But actually, during the fitting...
Well, in the final cut,
he only wore the dog ears.
He only wore the dog ears,
he didn't actually wear the dog tail.
But when he was trying out the look,
when he put on the dog tail,
he was a little shy.
And why didn't he wear it in the end?
Because it was a bit inconvenient for moving around,
so he didn't wear it.
Actually, many viewers are also very curious.
Little brother turned into a "tank" this season.
How does he feel about it?
Actually, we,
we also clearly felt this season that little brother
is very brave about stepping forward,
shielding everyone behind him
when the lights go out.
And actually, during the breaks in recording,
I asked him if he
had secretly played escape rooms
to secretly practice.
Like, why did he get so brave
all of a sudden this season? And...
But I never expected his answer to be,
"Someone in the family has to stand in front of everyone."
Before, it was Brother Bai.
And since Brother Bai isn't here this season,
he wanted to try hard to become like Brother Bai.
When I heard that,
I was actually quite surprised.
Because he didn't tell me that he was no longer afraid.
He actually just felt that
someone needed to step up right now,
so he chose to take a step forward.
Little brother has grown up.
Little brother has really grown up.
Please, bro,
please, bro,
let your little brother have it.
Okay, besides our regular players,
our Guest Stars each time have also won the love of many viewers.
MC (Little Sheep): Our Guest Stars each time
MC (Little Sheep): have also won the love of many viewers.
MC (Little Sheep): Today, for some reasons,
MC (Little Sheep): the PD for our Guest Stars
MC (Little Sheep): couldn't make it to our set.
MC (Little Sheep): But she very thoughtfully recorded for us
MC (Little Sheep): the little moments she shared with the Guest Stars.
MC (Little Sheep): So I'll read it on her behalf.
MC (Little Yang): Wang Yuwen is very assertive
MC (Little Yang): and full of ideas.
MC (Little Yang): During her makeup test,
MC (Little Yang): she knew exactly what she wanted,
MC (Little Yang): knew what suited her best,
MC (Little Yang): and how her clothes should be tailored.
MC (Little Yang): She even noticed the tiniest details.
MC (Little Yang): She's so professional
MC (Little Yang): that she could practically be a designer.
MC (Little Yang): She mentioned she doesn't usually play escape rooms
MC (Little Yang): or deduction games.
MC (Little Yang): But she memorized her script very quickly,
MC (Little Yang): and she shared many of her own ideas about the clues.
MC (Little Yang): When pre-recording clues and voiceovers,
MC (Little Yang): she even grabbed a tissue
MC (Little Yang): to act out crying.
MC (Little Yang): She also said if there was a scary part on set
MC (Little Yang): that she didn't actually find scary,
MC (Little Yang): she'd just complain about it right there.
MC (Little Yang): She's just so genuine
MC (Little Yang): and straightforward.
MC (Little Yang): She even noticed a PD's hands shaking
MC (Little Yang): and told the PD to get some rest.
MC (Little Yang): Wang Yuwen got into the story and deduction very fast, too.
MC (Little Yang): During voting,
MC (Little Yang): she kept debating whether Zhang Linghe was lying
MC (Little Yang): or just simply forgot.
MC (Little Yang): She even analyzed it, saying,
MC (Little Yang): "He's a science major,
MC (Little Yang): so he must have a good memory."
MC (Little Yang): But in the end, she still chose to believe He Jiahuan.
MC (Little Yang): She really likes segments with a sense of progress.
MC (Little Yang): Although the puppet scared her to tears,
MC (Little Yang): she said she isn't afraid of physical things,
MC (Little Yang): only the supernatural.
MC (Little Yang): She isn't afraid of things like bungee jumping,
MC (Little Yang): and she actually enjoys thrilling activities.
MC (Little Yang): But when it comes to ghosts or zombies,
MC (Little Yang): she's terrified.
MC (Little Yang): She said she has to wear earplugs when sleeping.
MC (Little Yang): She needs complete silence,
MC (Little Yang): otherwise she starts imagining things
MC (Little Yang): and scares herself.
MC (Little Yang): Even though she's easily scared
MC (Little Yang): of ghosts and the dark,
MC (Little Yang): she kept saying she wanted
MC (Little Yang): to challenge herself on this show.
MC (Little Yang): Later, when she was scared to tears again in the puppet room,
MC (Little Yang): she still insisted on opening the box.
MC (Little Yang): Her memory is also great.
MC (Little Yang): She remembered many clues very clearly.
MC (Little Yang): During the recording,
MC (Little Yang): Wang Yuwen was constantly immersed in the character and story.
MC (Little Yang): When facing puzzles and pun questions,
MC (Little Yang): she kept saying,
MC (Little Yang): "This is what our dad taught us."
MC (Little Yang): When she got it right,
MC (Little Yang): everyone in the control room applauded her.
MC (Little Yang): Then the next segment is about Sun Qian.
MC (Little Yang): To prepare for the show, Sun Qian
MC (Little Yang): even went to play a murder mystery game.
MC (Little Yang): At first, she thought
MC (Little Yang): she was assigned the killer role
MC (Little Yang): and said she'd definitely give herself away.
MC (Little Yang): She was super worried.
MC (Little Yang): Because she wrote in her questionnaire
MC (Little Yang): that she was okay with being the killer,
MC (Little Yang): she jokingly said,
MC (Little Yang): "I said I could be the killer in the questionnaire,
MC (Little Yang): so you actually made me the killer?"
MC (Little Yang): But actually, the setting we played
MC (Little Yang): in that episode was a fake killer.
MC (Little Yang): At night, she even got friends together to study the story,
MC (Little Yang): doing her homework seriously.
MC (Little Yang): When we were doing the defense session,
MC (Little Yang): she said I was just like a teacher
MC (Little Yang): because I kept asking her questions.
MC (Little Yang): While walking down the corridor,
MC (Little Yang): even though she was terrified,
MC (Little Yang): she kept comforting herself that it was fine.
MC (Little Yang): She really overcame her fears in the end.
MC (Little Yang): She even thought we were targeting her
MC (Little Yang): and made this design specifically for her fears.
MC (Little Yang): Actually, those are regular segments in Let's Start Deduction.
MC (Little Yang): But she performed really well in the end.
MC (Little Yang): Even though she joked about quitting and running away midway,
MC (Little Yang): a lot of her analysis was spot on.
Before voting, she even asked us for pen and paper.
She drew a floor plan herself.
And kept reviewing the entire trick route.
Midway, she even wanted to ask for outside help.
So her friends could help her analyze it.
After recording the previous case,
she went back and kept muttering, "What should I do?"
She even seriously asked an AI,
"What to do if you're easily scared?"
After going back,
she did homework for a whole night.
She watched show clips all night long.
And said she grew up overnight.
Indeed, in the later recordings,
she really improved a lot.
When walking the corridor alone,
she didn't use a Skill Card.
After hearing the walkie-talkie,
she was the first to realize
that someone might have walked the corridor alone
and killed Tui Nengzao.
When the kitchen collapsed,
she was also the first
to figure out that everyone needed to go down.
She even compared this task to "It Takes Two,"
saying it required everyone's cooperation.
Throughout the entire process,
she kept coming up with strategies.
For the last ball, she also pushed it up
with all her might along with everyone else.
She even said she could go up.
When changing into safety gear,
she kept reminding everyone
to make sure they wore their gear properly.
Next is for Chaoyue.
Chaoyue is very afraid of bugs.
Once, she saw on the hotel carpet
the body of a bug,
and got so scared she jumped onto the sofa.
But during the costume fitting,
she was full of ideas.
When trying on the swordswoman outfit,
she carefully adjusted the hem of the skirt
and repeatedly checked the mirror.
She noticed even the smallest details.
She was also very serious when going over the script.
She kept confirming various plots and phrases.
She was also extremely curious.
When playing mini-games, she kept asking,
"What is this prop?"
"What is that prop?"
Later, when we got to the set
and found out everyone chose food,
she finally realized...
she finally realized.
She said she finally knew why everyone chose food.
In the jail cell,
even though she was terrified,
she still completed the mission.
She was also very decisive when voting.
She didn't hesitate much.
After coming out, she quickly wrote down
the killer she chose.
She wouldn't obsess over
whether she was right or wrong in the end.
She's a very cute girl.
Every time we went over the cards,
she carefully read her Character Card.
When deducing,
she also thought very seriously
and tried hard to analyze things herself.
She really loves good food.
After eating at the Dining Table,
MC (Xiaoyang) Even when touching up her makeup,
MC (Xiaoyang) she would share her tasty snacks
MC (Xiaoyang) with the staff.
MC (Xiaoyang) She'd say the lychee cakes were so good
MC (Xiaoyang) and ask everyone to try them.
MC (Xiaoyang) Often, right after touching up,
MC (Xiaoyang) she'd turn around and start eating again.
MC (Xiaoyang) She also told everyone
MC (Xiaoyang) she was terrified of getting hate once it aired.
MC (Xiaoyang) She worried she might seem unable to keep up.
MC (Xiaoyang) But everyone on set thought she played great
MC (Xiaoyang) and kept telling her not to worry.
MC (Xiaoyang) Halfway through the recording,
MC (Xiaoyang) even though she was completely exhausted,
MC (Xiaoyang) she'd give it 120% as soon as cameras rolled,
MC (Xiaoyang) snapping right back into the zone.
MC (Xiaoyang) She truly loves deduction.
MC (Xiaoyang) She's played murder mysteries and escape rooms.
MC (Xiaoyang) She's just so carefree
MC (Xiaoyang) and extremely cute.
MC (Xiaoyang) Next up is a segment about Zhang Ruonan.
MC (Xiaoyang) When I called Nannan before the shoot,
MC (Xiaoyang) I could tell she was a very sincere
MC (Xiaoyang) and lovely girl.
MC (Xiaoyang) When going over her Character Card,
MC (Xiaoyang) she took it so seriously.
MC (Xiaoyang) Like a curious little kid,
MC (Xiaoyang) she kept asking all sorts of questions.
MC (Xiaoyang) Naturally, she worried about her performance,
MC (Xiaoyang) terrified of holding everyone back.
MC (Xiaoyang) She's incredibly polite.
MC (Xiaoyang) She says thank you no matter what she does.
MC (Xiaoyang) On the first day, after getting her makeup done,
MC (Xiaoyang) she was so happy.
MC (Xiaoyang) She even said she had big bright eyes.
MC (Xiaoyang) She really looked like a little rabbit.
MC (Xiaoyang) She's also great at taking care of others.
MC (Xiaoyang) She'd take the initiative to pour drinks for everyone.
MC (Xiaoyang) During filming, she'd constantly search for evidence.
MC (Xiaoyang) Right before we started filming each time,
MC (Xiaoyang) she'd say she forgot everything.
MC (Xiaoyang) But when she actually started telling her story,
MC (Xiaoyang) she'd tell it so well.
MC (Xiaoyang) She explained many details very clearly.
MC (Xiaoyang) To be able to tell it so immersively,
MC (Xiaoyang) and so naturally,
MC (Xiaoyang) means she truly understood the whole story.
MC (Xiaoyang) She is also highly competitive,
MC (Xiaoyang) and would get nervous about not performing well.
MC (Xiaoyang) So she kept trying hard to search for evidence,
MC (Xiaoyang) wanting to keep up with everyone's pace.
MC (Xiaoyang) After Nannan was tricked by Sis Jin,
MC (Xiaoyang) she felt incredibly regretful,
MC (Xiaoyang) thinking she was so silly.
MC (Xiaoyang) She kept joking about wanting to go home.
MC (Xiaoyang) All her analysis was perfectly sound
MC (Xiaoyang) and stayed on the right track.
MC (Xiaoyang) She has a mind of her own
MC (Xiaoyang) and isn't easily swayed by others.
MC (Xiaoyang) Everyone thought whatever she did was adorable.
MC (Xiaoyang) In the pancake stall area,
MC (Xiaoyang) she tried her best to be a good waitress,
MC (Xiaoyang) serving tea and water,
MC (Xiaoyang) and also calming the customers down.
MC (Xiaoyang) She was truly so dedicated.
MC (Xiaoyang) Searching for evidence while making pancakes,
MC (Xiaoyang) and still searching while everyone was interacting.
MC (Xiaoyang) After a brief adjustment period in the first case,
MC (Xiaoyang) she improved a lot.
MC (Xiaoyang) Even though she's a new player,
MC (Xiaoyang) she kept working hard on her analysis
MC (Xiaoyang) and would proactively share her thoughts.
MC (Xiaoyang) She even brought up several brilliant deduction points.
MC (Xiaoyang) Everyone praised her for being smart.
MC (Xiaoyang) She's also very caring.
MC (Xiaoyang) When she saw the tray table on Sis Jin's chair drooping,
MC (Xiaoyang) she took the initiative to help fix it.
MC (Xiaoyang) Seeing Sis Jin wear a veil as a scarf on her head,
MC (Xiaoyang) and use it like a hula hoop,
MC (Xiaoyang) she laughed so happily,
MC (Xiaoyang) laughing till her eyelashes fell off.
MC (Xiaoyang) When she got the undercover role,
MC (Xiaoyang) she instantly got excited again.
MC (Xiaoyang) During our previous chats,
MC (Xiaoyang) she mentioned she was quite good at
MC (Xiaoyang) this kind of deceptive mission.
MC (Xiaoyang) Normal players don't really want to be the killer,
MC (Xiaoyang) finding it too stressful.
MC (Xiaoyang) But she was actually okay with it.
MC (Xiaoyang) It's just that she hadn't completely
MC (Xiaoyang) played this kind of role before,
MC (Xiaoyang) so she didn't know how to play it at first.
MC (Xiaoyang) But with each day of filming,
MC (Xiaoyang) she adapted a bit more
MC (Xiaoyang) and made new progress.
MC (Xiaoyang) Once, she accidentally spilled a prop,
MC (Xiaoyang) and kept apologizing after coming out,
MC (Xiaoyang) saying she was sorry for ruining the prop.
MC (Xiaoyang) She's a very lively and lovely girl.
MC (Xiaoyang) After every recording, she'd ask me, "Sis PD,
MC (Xiaoyang) did I act well just now?"
MC (Xiaoyang) She actually
MC (Xiaoyang) has a strong heart.
MC (Xiaoyang) After getting the undercover role,
MC (Xiaoyang) she successfully hid it until the end,
MC (Xiaoyang) until Bro Ning started suspecting her.
MC (Xiaoyang) When touching up her makeup,
MC (Xiaoyang) she'd even take care of the makeup artist.
MC (Xiaoyang) To make their job easier,
MC (Xiaoyang) she'd stand with her legs spread wide.
MC (Xiaoyang) While visiting others,
MC (Xiaoyang) she helped Sis Jin take photos,
MC (Xiaoyang) literally lying on the floor in her princess dress.
MC (Xiaoyang) Truly a Chinese woman who lives for the perfect shot.
MC (Xiaoyang) Alright, thank you to the PDs for sharing.
MC (Xiaoyang) Our show has come to an end this season,
MC (Xiaoyang) but everyone's story will not end.
MC (Xiaoyang) Also, thank you to every PD for your sincere dedication to the show,
MC (Xiaoyang) and thank you to every viewer
MC (Xiaoyang) who has always supported "Let's Start Deduction".
MC (Xiaoyang) I hope "Let's Start Deduction" Season 5
MC (Xiaoyang) can meet you all soon.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei) Thank you everyone.
Zhou Keyu PD (Shiyi) See you next season.
Liu Yuning PD (Xiaoqi) Thank you for being with us.
Ding Chengxin PD (Dada) Thank you everyone.
Zhang Linghe PD (Weiwei) Thank you for your support.
MC (Xiaoyang) Okay, bye!